Stefan Higgins

stfn.work | github | stefanhiggins@uvic.ca | 416-931-5349

Summary

Researcher and technical communicator interested in technology, ethics of technology, and combining technical, design-based, and social science perspectives. Experienced in academic and public research and policy development, technical support and technical writing, and customer service. Also knowledgeable in web development, general purpose programming, and data analysis.

Work Experience

Digital Editor and Lead Researcher, Research Data Management for Humanists, University of Victoria (2021)

- Lead author (90%) of report on data infrastructure and management in Canada
- Research: independently developed research question and literature review, identified key stakeholders, made policy recommendations, and submitted report to deadline
- · Project management: planned 600-person virtual workshop, developed pre- and post-event surveys
- Performed qualitative data analysis, transcribed event videos for accessibility, built event Wiki, contributed to working group sessions

Senior Learning Technology Assistant, Learning and Teaching and Support and Innovation, University of Victoria (2020)

- *Project management*: supervised team of 4 providing technical support, customer service, course building, programming fixes, and technical writing for help documentation
- · Successfully onboarded faculty and students on-the-fly to new CMS under shifting and tight deadlines
- Adopted agile methodologies for project management, solved course problems, improved technical help documentation, and proposed standards for WYSIWYG editor use

Researcher and Research Assistant, The Praxis Studio, University of Victoria (2018-2020)

- Research: participated in independent and team-based projects on topics related to technology and technology use today and historically, including fact-checking and resource-building work
- Project management: project planning and budgeting, delegation of research duties, event planning, producing original research reports
- . Editorial: copyedited and edited two books for academic and public publication

Legislative Policy Researcher, Office of Andrew Weaver, MLA and Leader of BC Green Party (2014-2015)

- Research: produced background briefs for use in policy development and public communications (topics: BC energy use and agriculture)
- Data work: collected and analysed data to examine long-term policy approaches to topic areas
- Summarised and interpreted complex information for public communications, including writing blog posts

Miscellaneous Customer Service Positions (2012-2017)

- · Sales Associate, Australian Boot Company
- · Sales Associate, Walking on a Cloud
- · Supervisor, Shoppers Drug Mart
- · Sales Associate, Gap Inc.

Skills

Experienced	Knowledgeable
Atom	Python
Sublime Text	R
HTML	SQL
CSS	Git (porcelain)
Markdown	GitHub
Plain language	Unix shell commands
YAML	ArcGIS
Jekyll	Adobe CC
qualitative methods for social sciences	quantitative methods for social sciences

Other Relevant Skills:

- · Technical support and communication
- Content Management Systems (EdTech, Wordpress, Squarespace, etc.)
- · Designing and teaching material on technology
- MS Office
- Game Design (see cards and manual here)

Education

MA, University of Victoria, English

- Conceived of, planned, and managed complex research project on public communication of science and technology
- Won prize for best graduate research, and SSHRC Canada Graduate Scholarship to support outstanding research
- Published freelance writing on social media use and book reviews

BA, University of Toronto, Human Geography

- Research focus: urban policy and planning, sociology of cities
- Won prize for best undergraduate research in urban policy

Certifications

- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Coursera
- Introduction to Web Development, Lighthouse Labs
- · Digital Design, Toronto Image Works

Languages

- English
- French
 - Government of Canada second official language qualification level B, which is professional working competency